So we're back, and we're going to be looking at pages.
欢迎回来，让我们继续来关注页面
In the previous module,we looked at building our very first empty web application.
在之前的模块中，我们着眼于构建我们第一个空的 Web 应用程序
But it didn't really do much, right?
但它并没有太大的作用，对吧？
It just returned a string.
它只是返回一个字符串
And when I think about building a page,I don't know if you think about this the same way.
当我考虑构建一个页面时，我不知道你是否以同样的方式思考这个问题
Actually I do.
当然是的
I want to see some HTML.
我想看到一些 HTML
I want to see a physical page structure, and if you actually go back to the project folder
我想看到一个可见的页面结构，并且如果你回到项目文件夹
like all the files that we have, I don't see a single page.
在我们所有的文件中，我没有看到一个页面
Right, this is not page focused right now,it's string focused.
对，现在这并不是专注于网页，它专注于字符串
And while I could go in and maybe bold face,Beyonce, it's gonna break down very quickly.
虽然我可以修改字符串，也许可以添加加粗效果，Beyonce ，这会很快让人疯掉的
Yeah.
是的
So, we need a page-focused framework.
所以，我们需要一个专注于页面的框架
We do.
确实如此
And just to bring it back even just a little bit more,you talked about ConfigureServices and Configure.
现在让我们往上回滚一小部分，你谈到了 ConfigureServices 和 Configure ( Method )
And we're gonna configure our first service here.
然后我们要在这里配置我们的第一个服务
Right.
对
Yeah, so, if you type services.AddMVC.
嗯，所以，如果你输入 services.AddMVC
So if I type services.Add,I get all these choices
在我输入 services.Add 之后，我得到了所有这些选择
That we saw before.
我们之前也看到过
And these are all the different things that can be layered on top of our application.
这些不同的选项都会在 VS Code 上弹出显示（指代码提示）
And it's important to understand, like we talked about before, when we pop back out to Program.cs.
所以重要的是要理解，就像我们之前所说的那样，当我们回到 Program.cs （文件）
This is just a Main, remember we did a console app a second ago,
这只是一个 Main 函数，记得我们之前做过一个控制台应用程序
but we're building up this pipeline of services.
但我们正在构建服务的 pipeline （管道）
So what service do you want me to add?
那么你想要我添加什么样的服务？
MVC.AddMVC.
MVC AddMVC
So this is gonna add all the model view controller services that I would potentially want to use.
这将添加所有可能想要用的 MVC 服务 （ M - 模型， V - 页面， C - 控制器）
Okay, now I added it.
好的，现在我已经把它添加上了
There was a squiggle, and then the squiggle was gone.
有一个波浪，然后波浪消失了
Did it just magically become Mvcf?
它是不是神奇地变成了 MVC 框架？
No, cuz remember, we configure our services,and then we need to configure.
不，请记住，我们配置我们的服务，然后我们需要配置
So we actually have to use it.
实际上，我们必须使用它
Have to use them.
对的
We add them and then we use them.
我们添加它们，然后我们使用它们
Yeah.
嗯
Okay.
好的
So we app.UseMvc?
我们键入 app.UseMvc ？
And I don't think we need.
我认为我们不需要
It's worth pointing out all the different use stuff.
值得指出的是，在这有所有不同的用途的 Use
A lot of them.
确实有很多
There's your Facebook, your Google.
这有你的 Facebook ，你的 Google
Mm-hm.
嗯哼
Your different, what's called middleware,
各类不同的，所谓的中间件
you'll here about middleware during the advanced stuff,
你会在这里的高级内容了解中间件
but this where making some middleware right now.
但是现在先让我们来使用一些中间件
There's two options there, the default route or the regular UseMvc, we're just gonna say UseMvc by itself.
有两个选项，默认路由或经常使用的 UseMvc ，我们在这就使用 UseMvc （ Method ）
There's a bunch of options you can pass in.
有很多选项可以传入
We'll talk a little bit about routing later.
稍后我们会谈谈一些关于路由的问题
So, I say UseMvc.
看下 UseMvc
So, now Mvc is in the pipeline.
所以，现在 Mvc 在管道中
Yeah, so we can start taking advantage of it.
嗯，所以我们可以开始利用它
I don't think you would need the last lines though.
我不认为你会需要最后一行
Well, let's find out if it still runs.
好吧，让我们来看看它是否还能运行
All we've done is AddMVC, and UseMvc.
我们所做的只是 AddMVC 和 UseMvc
Does Hello Beyhive still happen? Yes.
Hello Beyhive 还会在吗？是的
Now it's bold,because I bold-faced it.
现在它被加粗了，因为我把它加粗了
So that points out that it's in the pipeline but it didn't change the behavior of anything.
因此，可以指出的是它正在管道中，但是它什么都没有改变
Yeah, cuz it hasn't been used at this point.
是的，因为在这里它没有被使用
Well, we havent added any pages.
好吧，我们还没有添加任何页面
I do not think,
所以，我并不这样想
since we're going to be using MVC,I don't think we need app.Run any more.
因为我们将要使用 MVC 我并不认为我们会需要 app.Run
I wanna keep it in there, though.
不过，我想保留在那里
If you don't mind,
如果你不介意的话
because when we add our pages, I wanna see the relationship between this, which is now called the default route.
因为当我们添加我们的网页时，在默认路由的情况下，我想看到页面与此之间的关系
The default route.
至于默认路由
This is the thing that happens, if this doesn't happen.
如何默认路由不起作用，那么这些将被执行
In the sense of, it runs in order.
就其意义而言，它将按顺序运行
Yes.
是的
Does that make sense?
这有合理吗？
Yeah.
是啊
So let's do the pages you wanna add,
那么，让我们来完成你想添加的页面，
and see if Beyonce shows up randomly.
看看 Beyonce 是否会随机出现
Yeah, and you mentioned something pretty significant for a lot of newbies.
对，你提到了一件对很多新手来说非常重要的事情
Is that the order in which a code is written matters?
这是代码的编写顺序吗？
It's very much does,especially when you're adding and using things in turn order.
这很重要，特别是当您依次添加和使用事物时
I believe that, if we went and move MVC down here,we will have a very different experience.
我相信，如果我们把 MVC 放在这里，我们将有非常不同的体验
Exactly.
没错
And we can maybe experiment with that once we add a few things.
我们可以尝试添加一些东西
Yeah, that's add in.
是的，再补充一些东西
Okay.
好的
Okay, so first thing I wanna do is add a new folder.
好吧，我想要做的第一件事就是添加一个新文件夹
All right.
对的
Yeah.
嗯
So I'm over here in a Visual Studio code, and I can right click, and say New Folder, or I can click these buttons.
在 Visual Studio Code 中的这个区域，我可以右击，然后新建文件夹，或者我可以点击这些按钮
I'm gonna right click and say a New Folder, because I have found that depending  on what's currently clicked on,
当右击的时候会出现 New Folder，是因为在当前点击的地方可以新建文件夹
when you see New Folder-    >> You might end up somewhere else?
当你看到显示 New Folder  -            >> 你要在别的地方建文件夹嘛？
It can sometimes be like one folder down,so just gonna watch out for that.
它有时可能会在某个文件夹里面，要注意这一点
So, I'm confirming that my Pages folder, you had me add,is at the same level and not accidentally In wwwroot
所以，我确认了我的 Pages 文件夹，你要求我添加，在同一级目录而不是在wwwroot中
Or in the end or wherever.
或者任何其他地方
So, it can be a little confusing, all right?
它可能有点混乱，是吗？
So, I have a Pages folder.
所以，我有一个Pages文件夹
Okay, and now we actually had to need to add a page.
好的，现在我们实际上需要添加一个页面
So if you add New File,and we're going to add a Index.cshtml.
所以如果你添加新文件，我们将添加一个Index.cshtml
C# HTML.
C# HTML
Yes, so I always call it C# HTML,
是的，我总是称它为 C# HTML ，
but I was told that that wasn't right.
但是我被告知这是不对的
It's not, it's just a RAZOR PAGE.
这没什么，它只是一个 RAZOR 页面
It's just a RAZOR PAGE, yes.
这只是一个 RAZOR 页面，是的
Okay, ignore that extension.
好的，忽略这个扩展拓展名
Okay.
嗯
That's so clearly says, yes HTML.
很明显，这就是 HTML
Okay.
好的
-All right? -It does.
-是吗？ -的确如此
So first thing I wanna do is add a page directive.
我想要做的第一件事就是添加一个页面指令
So it'd be @page.
所以应该是 @page
Okay so, @page, so directive starts with @.
好吧， @page ，所以指令以@开始
-Yeah -Okay.
-好 -是的
And we'll be seeing a couple of those throughout the day,and seeing what you can do with that.
我们将在今天看到其中的好几个（指令），并且了解你可以用它们做什么
All right.
好滴
We're just gonna write some HTML, so let's just use a h1.
我们只是要写一些 HTML ，所以我们只需要使用 h1
Okay, h, I get IntelliSense, which is nice.
好，我看到了非常棒的智能感知（ IntelliSense ）
Hello Beyonce.
Hello Beyonce
Imagine if Beyonce actually learns how code on one of these videos.
想象一下， Beyonce 是否真的通过这些视频学习了如何编程
And I don't have a fancy keyboard.
我键盘上没有这些特殊符号
You wanna make sure you
你想确保你
I gotta respect her.
我得尊重她
You gotta respect the Bey.
你必须尊重 Bey
There we go.
让我们继续吧
She will appreciate that when one day,when she does watch this video.
有一天，她会感激你的，当她看这个视频
When she does watch this and invite me to her house for lunch.
当她看到这个后邀请我到她家吃午饭
All right, do I need to do anything else?
好了，我还需要做其他事吗？
Yeah, did you save it?
嗯哼，你保存了吗？
Yeah.
是的
So let's just see what happens, let's run this.
让我们看看会发生什么，让我们来运行这个
All right.
好的
Do, do, do, gonna go and run it.
加油，继续，让我看到它运行起来
It's gonna fire up localhost:5000.
它会监听 localhost:5000
All right.
嗯哼
Wow.
哇
That's interesting.
这很棒
So Index.cshtml appears to be the default.
所以 Index.cshtml 似乎是默认的（页面）
Yes.
是的
And I wonder if I change its name Okay?
我想知道我是否可以改名？
Let's give it a try
让我们试试看
And then just hit Refresh.
然后点击刷新
No, you'd actually now have to-
哦不，你现在实际上应该-
No, look, where does that string come from?
不不不，快看，该字符串是从哪里来的？
It came from line, go back.
它来自那行，让我们倒回去
Yeah, it came from line 31.
是的，它来自第31行
Right, so the point here is that, UseMvc,added some default routing, some behavior.
对，所以这里要说的是 UseMvc 添加了一些默认路由及一些行为
Yeah.
是的
When we say routing it's like when the URL comes in,it has to make a decision about who's handling this.
我们所说的路由，就像是有 URL 进来一样，它必须决定谁来处理这件事
Exactly, so if you went back to your page,and you did /fred ,would it pop up?
没错，如果你回到你的页面，并且你添加了 /fred ，它会显示什么？
That's a good question.
这是个很好的问题
Yes, okay so now we are starting to learn a little bit about the behavior.
对，好吧 现在我们开始对这种行为有所了解了
So by default, just because it's called Index, some magic,
所以默认情况下，它被叫做 Index 这是一个特别的名称
not magic with MVC defaults it adds as the a default route.
而 MVC 在默认情况下，则会将它作为默认路由
Right, right.
对对
Okay, so if we added another page,and maybe we're going a bit too crazy here.
好的，如果我们添加了另一个页面，也许我们这里太疯狂了
Mm-hm, want to add another named page?
Mm-hm，想添加另一个被命名的页面？
Named page, yeah.
是的，被命名的页面
Okay, what do you want to call it?
好吧，你想把它叫作什么？
Solange?
Yeah, or Rihanna, or if, whatever you want.
可以，或者 Rihanna ，都可以啦
All right, so, okay here's another one.
好吧，这里有另一个
This page is at I'm thinking it's at-/Solange, right?
我认为这个页面会出现在 /Solange 对吗？
That's right.
没错
Yeah.
嗯哼
So, we'll just put that in the paragraph tag to be correct.
所以，我们只需将它放在段落标记（  ）中即可
See how Visual Studio code is trying to be helpful?
看到 Visual Studio Code 是怎么帮助你的了吗？
I should have just opened up my P to start with.
我应该在一开始就键入段落标记的开头 ()
There we go.
继续吧
So there is our default.
我们所有都是默认的
Did I not run it again?
我没有重新运行它吗？
I don't think you did.
我想你没有
Okay, so I dotnet run.
好吧，键入 dotnet run
So, there's our default.
这是我们的默认页面
And.That one is not showing up.
另一个没有出现
It is not.
这并不是
Why don't we put it in a folder.
为什么我们不把它放在一个文件夹中
Within a folder? Okay.
放在一个文件夹中？好吧
And then, call it Index.
然后，将其称为 Index
So, it would have to be Solange/Index then.
所以，它必须是 Solange/Index 吗？
No, cuz Index is the default.
不，因为 Index 是默认值
Interesting.
有意思
Hello Beyhive.
Hello Beyhive
Let's think about this.
让我们来思考一下
What are we doing wrong?
我们做错了什么？
This is good though, because we are doing a- We are doing an experiment.
没关系，因为我们正在做一个做一个实验
Doing an experiment here and in the process.
在这过程中进行实验
We are learning how things work and doing things wrong, right?
我们正在了解这些如何运作，可哪里出错了，对吗？
We are gonna do things together.
我们一起来解决它吧
So, I've just changed that real quick, we did Fred before.
所以，我刚刚改变了这里，我们之前做过 Fred
I know what it is.
我知道哪里错了
-Tell me -All right, check this,friends, out lets go back put it back to Solange this is.
-快告诉我 -好吧，检查一下，朋友们，让我们回去把它改回 Solange
Okay, so here's Index.
好的，这里是 Index
Look very carefully, there's only a couple lines.
仔细看，这里只有几行
Here's Solange.
这是 Solange
We did not put the page directive.
我们没有放置页面指令
Yay.
好极了
Okay.
对的
Very interesting.
非常有趣
-Interesting, so -It is that that makes it magic,actually it runs if it doesn't see the page directive
-有趣，那么 -实际上在程序运行时候它神奇地完成了这一切，如果没有这个页面指令
and it's never going to.
这个页面将永远不会显示
That's not the way it needs to go.
这意味着它没必要显示
Doesn't have to work that way.
不必通过这样执行
So, that interesting did not know that I knew it,but like I knew it intuitively.
所以，这个坑我之前并不知道，但我凭直觉猜到了就是这样
But this is something
可这一些东西
that someone at home is going to encounter.
总会有初学者会遇到
Yeah, yeah, it absolutely is.
是的，绝对会有的
It's definitely something that you're going to encounter
这绝对是你将会遇到的
like we hit it, and it was the first thing I told you to do was to add a page directive.
就像我们被它坑到一样，所以，我告诉你，要做的第一件事就是添加页面指令
Yep, absolutely.
是的，一定要记住
And this actually brings up an interesting point about Visual Studio versus Visual Studio code.
这实际上也是一个有关 Visual Studio 与 Visual Studio Code 有趣的地方
When we switch over to Visual Studio later
在稍后我们使用 Visual Studio
we gonna add up using the template that are built in.
我们将使用内置的模板来添加内容
So, we gonna go and say file new razor page.
我们只需要创建一个新的 Razor Page 文件
Exactly.
没错
And we will get some stuff for free, because we are just making these texts files by ourselves
而且（模板）将会完成一部分的代码，因为我们仅是通过自己来完成这些文本文件
we bump into these kind of mistakes,so that's really interesting.
才碰到了这种错误，所以这真的很坑
That does bring up the question about the folder thing though,why don't we try that?
这确实提出了有关文件夹的问题，我们为什么不尝试一下呢？
Let's make a folder before that,and then we'll move this here.
让我们在那先创建一个文件夹，然后我们把它移动到这
Exactly.
没错
And then, change it to Index, which appears to be the default.
然后，将其重命名为默认值 Index
So, if you refresh the page.
那么，如果你刷新页面的话
Yes, same page
没错，是同一页面
But if I change it here.
但是如果我在这里改变它
So, just explore this for a second, it looks like that is
只需探索一下，看起来就是这样
not necessary the name of the file, but the path.
没有什么文件名是必须的，除了路径会不一样
So, your default route would be path and then another path,in this case the default page right there, you see?
所以，你的默认路由将是由路径，然后是另一条路径所组成，在这种情况下，默认页面就在那里，你看到了吗？
Yeah, so the route is the file structure then?
是的，所以说路由就是文件夹结构喽？
The route is the file structure.
对，路由就是文件结构
Which for a page focused framework is a really nice experience.
一个专注于页面的框架是一个非常好的体验
It makes total sense to me.
这对我来说意义重大
Right.
对啊
Like when you build your first HTML page ever it has the same experience.
就像你建立你的第一个 HTML 页面一样，这会是相同的体验
Yeah, that page within a folder.
是的，一个在文件夹中的页面
And that means that when we go later on and make customers,and products, and things like that
这意味着，我们在稍后会做类似消费者，生产者，以及物品的（应用）
it's gonna be really clear about how to do that.
这一思路应该是非常清晰的
This is just static HTML though.
而这仅仅的静态的 HTML
We should probably add something dynamic
我们应该再添加一些动态的东西
before we move on to the next section.
在我们进入下一节之前
So, let's give Solange some more information.
那么，让我们来给予 Solange 更多的信息
So, I hear she has a concert today.
我听说她在今天有一个音乐会
Okay, let's assume that it's always now,there is always a Solange concert.
哦好，让我们假设在当前时刻，总是会有 Solange 的音乐会
-There is always a -At any moment.
-那总有一个 -在任何时候
Exactly.
好的吧
So, we'll have bold thing and what should we say?
我们将会加粗这一信息，我们该怎么说呢？
The concert starts at, I don't know, 3pm, right?
音乐会将在什么时候开始，我不知道，下午3点可以吗？
but I wanna have that be dynamic.
但我希望它可以是动态的
Okay.
好吧
How can I make that now.
我应该怎么样让它显示现在的时刻
@DateTime.
@DateTime
So, I say, @, again.
好吧，我再次用了 @
Yeah.
对的
DateTime, which is like System.DateTime
DateTime ，就像是 System.DateTime
.Now
All right, come back, hit refresh, then hit refresh again.
很好，让我们回来看看，点击刷新，然后再次刷新
I'm late I gotta go.
要迟到了，我得走了
You gotta go, it's happening.
你确实得走了，它刚开始
It's happening right now.
它现在刚开始
Now, it's important to point out that,notice the difference between me making a change.
现在需要指出的是，注意我这样做的区别
Yep.
好的
Control + S, Alt + Tab, refresh.
保存，切换窗口，刷新
I'm not having to build.
我不需要构建
-No -Right.
-确实没有 -对吧
With razor pages the page is being built when it changes,and it gets hit for the very first time,
对 Razor 页面来说，当它在改变后将会自动构建，而且能很快的响应
if I change the C# files I need to then go and rebuild.
可如果我改变了 C# 文件，那我就需要重新构建项目
Okay, but within the page itself you do not need to do that.
对的，但如果是页面自身发生了变化，你就不需要这样做
So, the razor pages, these CSH developed pages.
这些使用 C# HTML 开发的 Razor 页面
They get copied to the host and
他们可以被复制到 host （运行应用程序的主机，或称宿主）
they are part of the source code.
他们也可以是源码的一部分
But these .cs files don't get copied to the host,
但是这些 .cs 文件没有被复制到 host
in fact the DLL that they build into does.
事实上，他们被构建为 DLL 文件
Okay.
好吧
Right，that's just a little important thing to point out,
对，这还有一个值得指出的要点
and you can see that if you go and say, dotnet build.
你可以看到这一过程，通过 dotnet build
We've been saying dotnet run.
我们在之前用的都是 dotnet run
Yeah.
对
See?
看到了吗？
See how it actually points to your web app?
看到它是如何指向你的 Web 应用了吗？
It says, mywebapp is right there.
这样说吧， mywebapp 就在这里
So, I have a question for you.
等下，我有一个问题问你
If someone on this, who's watching us right now.
如果有人正在看我们的视频，
Like what is that dll thing that he is talking about,
就像他正在讲的 dll 这类东西，
where they can learn more about that?
在哪可以让我们的观众了解更多？
All right, so that's called an assembly
好的，这被叫做程序集
it's a dynamic link library if you wanted to learn about
这是一个动态链接库，如果你想知道
the details of how assembly's works some things like that.
程序集是怎样工作的细节的话
You can go and take a look at some of
你可以去看一些
the intermediate sections on the job.
中间步骤
I just wanted to point out that
对此我想说的是
when I go and publish my application,like I'm meaning to say it's time for my app to go out into the world.
当我准备发布我的应用程序时，或者说当我准备让其他人来使用我的应用时
-We're gonna get -And just to be clear for
-我们将会得到 -就会清楚的知道
some people who are watching this.
谁看了这个视频
Publish it doesn't necessarily mean that you're going to hit dotnet publish and
发布应用并不意味着你只需键入 dotnet publish
somehow it's gonna magically appear on the website.
然后它就会神奇的出现在某个网站上
-Right -Yeah, I like
-是的 -对，我希望
I just mean that I need people to understand the difference between
我只是我希望大家能理解以下两者之间的不同
the source code that's in the C sharp files,and the razor pages that are gonna be copied up through the final location.
通过 C# 所写的源代码，与将被拷贝到最终位置的 Razor 页面
Cool, so this is a little bit of C sharp right here.
很好，这是一小部分的 C# （代码）
It is.
是的
Right, I wonder if I could cheat.
那我想知道我是否能够这样做
How much do you wanna cheat?
怎么样？
Well, we can write C sharp here, right?
我们在这写了 C# 代码，不是吗？
Can I say, 2+2?
那么，2 + 2 会可行吗？
What am I allowed to say in there?
我将会在这里得到什么？
Broke it?
出错了？
All right, so that got an error, right?
好吧，这将导致一个错误，是吧？
So, it doesn't like that.
所以，这并不像我想象的那样
What are the rules about what you can put in there.
那在这里添加 C# 代码的规则是什么
We will kind of explore that a little bit earlier,as we can say at, and then put chunks of code.
我们会稍微探讨一下，正如我们所做的这样，然后把大量的代码放在这里面。
Okay.
嗯嗯
All right, cool.
太棒了
So, that is dynamic, there's a concert starting immediately.
这是动态的，有一场音乐将马上开始。
And then, we'll come back a little bit and look at configuration.
我们将在稍后回来，再来聊一聊如何配置
All right.
稍后见